<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xliff version="2.1" srcLang="en-US" trgLang="ja">
  <file id="src" original="src.txt" datatype="plaintext">
    <unit id="1">
      <segment>
        <source>&gt; TO: PATAPHYSICS DEPARTMENT(ALL)
&gt; Ladies,
&gt; As many of you are aware, Pataphysics command has been working on an update on [[[sandrewswann-s-proposal|Dr.Swann's Narrative Sandwich model]]] to keep us up to date with Metanarrativics' recent research.</source>
        <target state="translated">&gt; 宛先: 空想科学部門（全員）
&gt; 各位、
&gt; 周知のとおり、空想科学司令部はメタ物語学の最新研究動向に対応すべく、[[[sandrewswann-s-proposal|スワン博士の物語サンドイッチ・モデル]]]の更新作業を進めてきた。</target>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="term">用語方針変更: "narrative" 系はカタカナ表記を避け「物語」で統一（例: Narrative Sandwich model→物語サンドイッチ・モデル, Metanarrativics→メタ物語学）。</note>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="register">"Ladies" は性別を限定しない呼称として「各位」。</note>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="3">
      <segment>
        <source>The document has now been released, and can be found [[span style="color:#b01;"]]here[[/span]].</source>
        <target state="translated">当該文書は既に公開されており、[[span style="color:#b01;"]]こちら[[/span]]で閲覧できる。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="4">
      <segment>
        <source>
&gt;
&gt; The gist of this update is the incorporation of Doctor Huever's Hypercanon theory, which holds that our reality is not a single narrative bulk below the Alpha layer, but an n-dimensional set of narrative planes connecting at defined conceptual points.</source>
        <target state="translated">
&gt;
&gt; 今回の更新の要旨はヒューバー博士のハイパーカノン理論の採用である。この理論は、我々の現実がアルファ層下にある単一の{{物語束^^narrative bulk^^}}ではなく、特定の{{概念点^^conceptual point^^}}で接続される n 次元の物語平面集合であるとする。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="5">
      <segment>
        <source>The most notable concentration of these points is, of course, the Database.</source>
        <target state="translated">これらの接点が最も顕著に集中する場所は、無論“データベース”である。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="6">
      <segment>
        <source>While the formation of these narrative planes is still being studied, the strongest coherent factor between them is Database Causal Inclusions - that is to say, instances of swn001-1 ("//Horror Writer Entities//").</source>
        <target state="translated">これらの物語平面がいかに形成されるかは未だ研究途上だが、平面間の最も強いコヒーレント因子は「データベース因果内包」、すなわち swn001-1（「//ホラー作家実体群//」）の存在である。
        </target>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="term">Database Causal Inclusion → データベース因果内包 / Horror Writer Entity → ホラー作家実体群 に統一。</note>
        <note appliesTo="source" category="comment">訳文にあまり自信がない。</note>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="7">
      <segment>
        <source>
&gt;
&gt; Our very own [http://www.scp-wiki.net/forum/t-1938548/the-grand-crosslinking| Operation FLAT HORIZON] has shown some success thus far in incorporating these planes, thus reducing their multiplicity.</source>
        <target state="translated">
&gt;
&gt; 我らが[http://www.scp-wiki.net/forum/t-1938548/the-grand-crosslinking|FLAT HORIZON作戦]はこれまでに、これらの平面を統合することに一定の成功を収め、その多重性を減じている。</target>
      </segment>
      <note appliesTo="target" category="register">"incorporating these planes"について、掌握する、出中に収め得るなど訳語を変えたほうが良いだろうか。</note>
    </unit>
    <unit id="8">
      <segment>
        <source>Our grasp on the Alpha layer has greatly increased in the last month alone as such.</source>
        <target state="translated">その結果、この 1 か月だけでも我々のアルファ層に対する理解は大きく向上した。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="9">
      <segment>
        <source>Knowing this, I propose we move to stage two of **Operation ÓverMeta**.</source>
        <target state="translated">以上を踏まえ、**ÓverMeta作戦**第2段階へ移行することを提案する。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="10">
      <segment>
        <source>With research into the mechanics of [[[SCP-1304]]] and observation of [[[scp-2916|SCP-2916-1]]] and [[[SCP-2747]]], subnarrative entities capable of acting on and escaping to their upper layer, Procedure Kuzco-Bueller has been developed by Subnarrativics, utilising [[[SCP-826]]], for the purpose of full narrative extraction - taking fictional entities and bringing them into our reality.</source>
        <target state="translated">[[[SCP-1304]]] の機構解析と、（上位層に作用しそこへ離脱する能力を有する下位物語実体である）[[[scp-2916|SCP-2916-1]]] および [[[SCP-2747]]] の観察結果を踏まえ、下位物語学は [[[SCP-826]]] を利用したクスコ・ビューラー手順を開発した。これは「物語の完全抽出」――フィクション上の実体を取り出して我々の現実層へ移入する――を目的とする。</target>
        <meta type="alternate-translation" key="1">SCP-1304 の機構研究と、上位層に干渉し脱出できる下位物語実体である SCP-2916-1 / SCP-2747 の観察に基づき、下位物語学は SCP-826 を用いるクスコ・ビューラー手順を策定した。目的は「物語の完全抽出」――フィクション中の実体を現実へ移すこと――である。</meta>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="clarification">用語方針更新: "fiction(al)" は「虚構」ではなく「フィクション」で統一。先行訳「虚構上の実体」を訂正。</note>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="11">
      <segment>
        <source>We plan to create a task force of hypernarrative entities with this procedure, enlisting the aid of [[[scp-423|our standard scout]]] as a recruiter, with the purpose of creating a new narrative plane under our influence that intersects with other narrative planes.</source>
        <target state="translated">この手順により超物語実体で構成されるタスクフォースを編成する計画である。[[[scp-423|標準スカウト]]]を勧誘担当として加え、他の物語平面と交差し我々の影響下に置かれる新規物語平面を創出する。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="12">
      <segment>
        <source>Put into plain English: we're going to make a canon.</source>
        <target state="translated">平たく言えば――自前の公式設定（カノン）を作る。</target>
        <meta type="alternate-translation" key="1">要するに、我々独自のカノンを立ち上げる。</meta>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="term">初出なので「公式設定（カノン）」と補足。</note>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="13">
      <segment>
        <source>
&gt;
&gt; Many of you may be wondering why I'm explaining so many concepts to you in this missive.</source>
        <target state="translated">
&gt;
&gt; この書簡でこれほど多くの概念を説明している理由を疑問に思っている者も多いだろう。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="14">
      <segment>
        <source>After all, this is old hat to anyone who's worked here for more than a few months.</source>
        <target state="translated">何しろ、数か月以上ここで勤務している者にはもはや常識だからだ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="15">
      <segment>
        <source>Some of the cleverest among you may already suspect the answer.</source>
        <target state="translated">勘の鋭い者は既に察しているかもしれない。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="16">
      <segment>
        <source>Ladies, this letter is our canon's introduction.</source>
        <target state="translated">諸君、この手紙こそが我々のカノンの導入だ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="17">
      <segment>
        <source>Welcome to the adventures of MTF-ι-0 ("NN"), reader.</source>
        <target state="translated">読者諸氏、MTF-ι-0（“NN”）の冒険へようこそ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="18">
      <segment>
        <source>God help us, let's not get deleted.</source>
        <target state="translated">神よ助け給え。削除あるなかれ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="19">
      <segment>
        <source>
&gt;
&gt; -Dr.</source>
        <target state="translated">
&gt;
&gt; -Dr.</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="20">
      <segment>
        <source>Penelope Panagiotopolous, Head of Pataphysics.</source>
        <target state="translated">空想科学部門長 ペネロペ・パナギオトポウロス</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="21">
      <segment>
        <source>


**The Crew:**


[[div style="margin:0; width:750px;"]]
||~ Name: ||Gordon Dancer||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-1||~ Callsign: || Nocter||
||~ Position: ||Squad Leader ||~ Recovered from:||||||  Helm, G. (2015) //Stronger Than Fiction//. Paris, France: Hachette.||
||||||||||||~ Member Bio:||
|||||||||||| Gordon is a persistent narrative entity who remembers all works he is placed in with respect to the chronology of his upper layer.</source>
        <target state="translated">


**クルー一覧:**


[[div style="margin:0; width:750px;"]]
||~ 名前: ||ゴードン・ダンサー||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-1||~ コールサイン: || ノクター||
||~ 職務: ||分隊長 ||~ 回収元:||||||  Helm, G. (2015) //Stronger Than Fiction//. パリ（フランス）: ハシェット||
||||||||||||~ メンバー概要:||
|||||||||||| ゴードンは、自身の上位層における時系列に沿って、自分が登場するすべての作品を記憶している、持続的な物語実態である。</target>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="register">Unit21〜49 をSCP報告書調（客観・簡潔・中立）へ改稿。</note>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="22">
      <segment>
        <source>He therefore remembers all drafts, works and fanworks he is placed into with total clarity.</source>
        <target state="translated">その性質により、登場させられた全ての下書き・本編およびファン創作を完全に記憶している。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="23">
      <segment>
        <source>Gordon has gained a notable internet following which places him within many crossover fanworks, primarily written fan fiction and fan art.</source>
        <target state="translated">ゴードンはインターネット上で多くのフォロワーを獲得し、その人気から、文章のファンフィクションやファンアートなどのクロスオーバー二次創作に頻繁に登場するようになった。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="24">
      <segment>
        <source>Prior to extraction, it was often seen that these fanworks would, over time, change to reflect Gordon's knowledge and memory.</source>
        <target state="translated">抽出以前、これらファン作品が時間経過とともにゴードンの知識・記憶を反映する方向へ改変される事例がしばしば観測された。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="25">
      <segment>
        <source>This was widely believed to be the work of the author as a continuation of Gordon's story, and were tracked on the web page [[span style="color:#b01;"]]www.reddit.com/r/whereintheworldisgordondancer[[/span]].</source>
        <target state="translated">これはゴードンの物語の続きとして作者が行ったものだと広く解釈され、ウェブページ[[span style="color:#b01;"]]www.reddit.com/r/whereintheworldisgordondancer[[/span]]上でその動向が追跡されていた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="26">
      <segment>
        <source>Since extraction, these edits have ceased. _</source>
        <target state="translated">抽出以降、当該改変は停止している。_</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="27">
      <segment>
        <source>
 _
 Gordon has expressed extreme displeasure in his role within the canon, and claims to have precognitive abilities stemming from the author "writing the end first like the fucking twat he is". Gordon has said numerous times that this story "does not fucking end well", but refuses to elaborate on this statement.||</source>
        <target state="translated">
 _
 ゴードンはカノン（正史）における自身の役割に強い不満を示し、作者が「クソ野郎らしく、結末を先に書く」ことに起因する予知能力を有すると主張する。ゴードンは「この物語はロクな終わり方をしねえ」と繰り返し発言しているが、その詳細を述べることは拒否している。||</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="28">
      <segment>
        <source>
||~ Name: ||Barker Sullivan||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-2||~ Callsign: || Intro||
||~ Position: ||Specialist ||~ Recovered from:||||||  Kaufmann, C. (2002) //Unpeople//. Manhattan, New York: HarperCollins.||
||||||||||||~ Member Bio:||
|||||||||||| Barker is an adaptive narrative entity who shifts in abilities, form and identity to suit the narrative she is currently placed in.</source>
        <target state="translated">
||~ 名前: ||バーカー・サリバン||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-2||~ コールサイン: || イントロ||
||~ 職務: ||スペシャリスト ||~ 回収元:||||||  Kaufmann, C. (2002) //Unpeople//. マンハッタン（ニューヨーク）: ハーパーコリンズ||
||||||||||||~ メンバー概要:||
|||||||||||| バーカーは、自分が現在置かれている物語に合わせて能力、姿、アイデンティティを変化させる、適応型の物語実体である。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="29">
      <segment>
        <source>Barker is the only character to appear in all 12 short stories within //Unpeople//. She also appears in the blurb and special thanks, and narrates the introduction and author biography.</source>
        <target state="translated">『Unpeople』に収録されている全12編の短編に登場する唯一のキャラクターである。彼女はまた、帯文や謝辞にも登場し、序文と作者略歴のナレーションも務めている。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="30">
      <segment>
        <source>Regardless of physical form, presentation, and personality, Barker will always identify as female.</source>
        <target state="translated">身体的な姿・外見・人格の如何にかかわらず、バーカーは常に女性として自己同定する。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="31">
      <segment>
        <source>In most of their identities, Barker has been diagnosed with Autistic Spectrum Disorder or some equivalent. _</source>
        <target state="translated">多くのアイデンティティにおいて、バーカーは自閉スペクトラム症、または同等概念と診断されている。_</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="32">
      <segment>
        <source>
 _
 Following extraction, Barker has assumed the form of a battle-hardened Jack of All Trades type, formerly the head of MTF-κ-19.</source>
        <target state="translated">
 _
 抽出後、バーカーは元MTF-κ-19の隊長であった、百戦錬磨の{{何でも屋^^ジャック・オブ・オール・トレーズ^^}}の姿をとっている。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="33">
      <segment>
        <source>The narrative requirement for this form is unknown.</source>
        <target state="translated">いかなる物語上の要請で、この姿を取っているのかは不明である。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="34">
      <segment>
        <source>A recent paper, //Pataphysical Anomaly Recursion both preceding and following Procedure Kuzco-Bueller//, puts forth the hypothesis that Barker's anomalous ability to adapt to a narrative is simply a by-product of adapting to fit into this canon's metanarrative.No way to test this hypothesis has yet been put forth.||

||~ Name: ||The Overvoid Lurk||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-xx||~ Callsign: || [[[operation-overmeta]]]||
||~ Position: ||Right in front of you ||~ Recovered from:||||||  Morrison, G. (2012) //Intergalactic//. Berkeley, California: Image Comics.||
||||||||||||~ Member Bio:||
||||||||||||</source>
        <target state="translated">最新の論文 //クスコ・ビューラー手順前後における空想科学的異常再帰// は、バーカーの物語に適応するという異常な能力は、このカノンのメタ物語への適合過程に伴う副次的産物であるとの仮説を提唱している。この仮説を検証する方法は、まだ提示されていない。

            ||~ 名前: ||オーバーヴォイド・ラーク||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-xx||~ コールサイン: || [[[operation-overmeta]]]||
            ||~ {{職務^^ポジション^^}}: || あなたの前 ||~ 回収元:||||||  Morrison, G. (2012) //Intergalactic//. バークレー（カリフォルニア）: Image Comics||
            ||||||||||||~ メンバー概要:||
            ||||||||||||
        </target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="35">
      <segment>
        <source>Overvoid is a narrative entity appearing both as and within a text.</source>
        <target state="translated">オーバーヴォイドは、テキストそのものとして、またその内部に現れる物語実体である。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="36">
      <segment>
        <source>Overvoid initially appeared as a copy of //Intergalactic #8// within //Intergalactic#8//, discovered by the character Ignoble Steed.</source>
        <target state="translated">オーバーヴォイドの初出は、『Intergalactic#8』内に登場する『Intergalactic #8』のコピーとして現れ、キャラクター「イグノーブル・スティード」により発見された。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="37">
      <segment>
        <source>At the end of the issue, it was revealed that Overvoid was also the narrator of //Wanderlust//, having gained sentience through its own presence within the text.</source>
        <target state="translated">号末において、オーバーヴォイドが『Wanderlust』の語り手であることが明かされた。彼は、文章内での自身の存在を通して知性を獲得していた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="38">
      <segment>
        <source>Overvoid's presence can be detected within a work when descriptors, text boxes and occasionally background text begin referring to themselves in the first person or attempting to converse with the reader.</source>
        <target state="translated">ある作品において、描写、テキストボックス、背景のテキストが、自身を一人称で語り始めたり、読者との対話を試みたりするようになることで、その作品内にオーバーヴォイドが存在していることを検知できる。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="39">
      <segment>
        <source>Possible relation to [[[SCP-426]]] is being researched. _</source>
        <target state="translated">[[[SCP-426]]]との関連可能性について調査中。_</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="40">
      <segment>
        <source>
 _
 Upon extraction, I became this webpage, hosted as a single HTML document both within our current layer/plane and the Alpha layer.[[footnote]]That's your reality, dear reader! [[/footnote]]　I'm an invaluable resource, they say, though they're rather annoyed I only allow them glimpses at me in moments of need.</source>
        <target state="translated">
 _
抽出後、私はこのウェブページになった。私は我々の現在の層/平面とアルファ層[[footnote]]親愛なる読者諸君、それこそが諸君の現実性だ！ - Obvious Overvoid[[/footnote]]の両方において、単一のHTMLドキュメントとしてホストされている。私はかけがえのないリソースだと、彼らは言う。もっとも、私が必要な時にしか姿を垣間見せないことには、彼らも少々苛立っているようだが。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="41">
      <segment>
        <source>I'm a narrative device as much as the rest of them, and they really need to respect my structure - if they had a handy roadmap at all times, where on earth would the conflict be?</source>
        <target state="translated">私も他の皆と同様に物語上の装置なのだから、まったく財団は私の{{立ち位置^^ストラクチャー^^}}を尊重する必要があるはずだ――いつも財団に便利なロードマップがあったら、一体どこに葛藤が生まれるというのだ？</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="42">
      <segment>
        <source>  _
 _
 I'm sorry, I'm babbling.</source>
        <target state="translated">  _
 _
すまない、饒舌になりすぎた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="43">
      <segment>
        <source>We really should get along to our final member…||


||~ Name: ||Reginald Impel||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-null||~ Callsign: || Dude in the Corner||
||~ Position: ||Foetal ||~ Recovered from:||||||  //N/A//||
||||||||||||~ Member Bio:||
|||||||||||| Reggie presented himself to the Pataphysics department on 26 Oct. 2015, claiming to be a self-insert character for Horror Writer Entity swn001-1-RMPL ("[[*user Rimple]]").</source>
        <target state="translated">では、いよいよ最後のメンバーの紹介に移るとしよう…。||


||~ 名前: ||レジナルド・インペル||~ ID: ||MTF-ι-0-null||~ コールサイン: || 隅の男||
||~ 職務: ||胎児（Foetal） ||~ 回収元:||||||  //該当なし//||
||||||||||||~ メンバー概要:||
|||||||||||| レジーは2015/10/26に自発的に空想科学部門へ出頭し、自身をホラー作家実体swn001-1-RMPL（"[[*user Rimple]]"）の自己投影キャラクターであると主張した。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="44">
      <segment>
        <source>Reggie is an extremely talented hacker and former head of the Foundation's IT department who hacked the Pataphysics database and figured out the implications of our research.</source>
        <target state="translated">レジーは極めて有能なハッカーで財団IT部門の元責任者であり、空想科学データベースをハッキングすることで本研究が含意するところを把握した。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="45">
      <segment>
        <source>Reggie claims to have no real backstory or personality of his own, which our research confirms. _</source>
        <target state="translated">レジーは自身に固有のバックストーリーや人格は存在しないと主張しており、これは我々の調査によっても裏付けられている。_</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="46">
      <segment>
        <source>
 _
 As attempts to remove Reggie from the narrative have proven unsuccessful, Reggie has been been assigned to MTF-ι-0, and is to accompany them at all times to allow for plot progression.</source>
        <target state="translated">
 _
 レジーを当物語から除去する試みが全て失敗に終わった。このためレジーはMTF-ι-0に配属され、プロットの進行を可能にするため常に同部隊に同行することになっている。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="47">
      <segment>
        <source>Reggie is to be regularly acknowledged for the purposes of nominal inclusion within the story.</source>
        <target state="translated">物語に名目上でも登場させる目的で、レジーは定期的に言及されることになっている。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="49">
      <segment>
        <source>Reggie is classified as an irritating narrative entity.||
</source>
        <target state="translated">レジーは厄介な物語実体として分類されている。||
</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="50">
      <segment>
        <source>

[[/div]]
-----


Director Panagiotopolous stood at the head of the table, lost for words. "What on earth have I got myself into with you two?"</source>
        <target state="translated">
[[/div]]
-----

パナギオトポウロス部門長は卓の上座で言葉を失っていた。「まったく、君たち二人と関わって、私は一体何に巻き込まれてしまったんだろう？」</target>
        <note appliesTo="target" category="style">物語調（語りの滑らかさ・台詞の自然さ）へ改稿。</note>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="51">
      <segment>
        <source>Evidently not //quite// lost, then.</source>
        <target state="translated">というわけで、//完全に//言葉を失っていたわけではない。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="52">
      <segment>
        <source>Gordon and Jasmine sat opposite her, both frowning.</source>
        <target state="translated">ゴードンとジャスミンが彼女の正面に座り、二人とも眉間にしわを寄せていた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="53">
      <segment>
        <source>
"Here, it wasn't my fucking idea to-" Gordon was interrupted by Reggie, screaming through his gag. "</source>
        <target state="translated">
「おい、ここに――これは俺のクソみたいな発案じゃ――」ゴードンの言葉は、猿ぐつわ越しに絶叫したレジーに遮られた。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="54">
      <segment>
        <source>Right, Reggie's here too.</source>
        <target state="translated">ああ、そうだ。レジーも居たんだった。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="55">
      <segment>
        <source>Whatever.</source>
        <target state="translated">どうでもいいけどな。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="56">
      <segment>
        <source>Point is, it wasn't my idea to drag me up here.</source>
        <target state="translated">要は、俺をここに引きずり上げる案は俺の発想じゃないって話だ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="57">
      <segment>
        <source>Fred made me think I'd be //escaping// the wanky meta bullshit by coming here."</source>
        <target state="translated">フレッドがさ、ここへ来りゃああの気取ったメタ臭い茶番から//抜け出せる//って信じ込ませたんだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="58">
      <segment>
        <source>
"That's on us, yes."</source>
        <target state="translated">
「それはこちらの責任、ではありますね。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="59">
      <segment>
        <source>Penelope said, her tone unapologetic.</source>
        <target state="translated">ペネロペは悪びれた様子もなく言った。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="60">
      <segment>
        <source>
"It's fucking on //them//," Gordon growled, jabbing a finger toward the ceiling. "</source>
        <target state="translated">
「いや、全部//あいつら//のクソみたいなせいだ」ゴードンは唸るように言い、天井を指差した。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="61">
      <segment>
        <source>The idiot who wrote us.</source>
        <target state="translated">俺たちを書いた間抜け野郎のな。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="62">
      <segment>
        <source>You're no more real than we are."</source>
        <target state="translated">あんたも俺たちと同じで現実の存在じゃないんだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="63">
      <segment>
        <source>
Jasmine pinched the bridge of her nose, sighing dramatically. "</source>
        <target state="translated">
ジャスミンは鼻梁をつまみ、大げさなため息を吐いた。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="64">
      <segment>
        <source>This is a terrible way to start the story," she said, to nobody in particular. "</source>
        <target state="translated">物語の始め方として最悪ね」と誰にともなく彼女は呟き、「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="65">
      <segment>
        <source>You realise this is the start of the story, right?"</source>
        <target state="translated">これが“物語の冒頭”だって自覚、あるんでしょうね？」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="66">
      <segment>
        <source>
Gordon hesitated for a second, then groaned as he sensed it himself. "</source>
        <target state="translated">
ゴードンは一瞬ためらい、自分でもそれを肌で感じ取って唸った。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="67">
      <segment>
        <source>Why do you think he's-" He stopped as it clicked. "</source>
        <target state="translated">なんであいつが――」舌打ちをし、言葉を切る。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="68">
      <segment>
        <source>Because he doesn't know where to go with us!</source>
        <target state="translated">俺たちをどう展開させればいいか分かってねぇんだよ！」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="69">
      <segment>
        <source>He's just writing, seeing where it takes him."</source>
        <target state="translated">ただ書き散らして、流れに任せてるだけだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="70">
      <segment>
        <source>
"So, wait, this isn't going in the final story, then?</source>
        <target state="translated">
「じゃあさ、これは最終稿には入らないってこと？」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="71">
      <segment>
        <source>Is this even real?</source>
        <target state="translated">これってそもそも“本物”なの？</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="72">
      <segment>
        <source>For us, I mean?</source>
        <target state="translated">――私たちにとって、って意味で？</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="73">
      <segment>
        <source>What happens if he gets bored and just

-----

**Draft 2:**

"So, ok, we're fighting a big tree?"</source>
        <target state="translated">もし彼が飽きて ただ――

-----

**ドラフト2:**

「で、つまり、大きな木と戦うってこと？」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="74">
      <segment>
        <source>Sally asked quizzically, looking up from the notepad she was doodling in.</source>
        <target state="translated">サリーは落書きしていたノートから顔を上げ、首をかしげながら尋ねた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="75">
      <segment>
        <source>
Penelope tapped the whiteboard again, gesturing to her scribbled diagrams. "</source>
        <target state="translated">
ペネロペはホワイトボードをコツコツ叩き、殴り書きの図を指し示した。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="76">
      <segment>
        <source>A //narrative// tree.</source>
        <target state="translated">//物語//の“木”だ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="77">
      <segment>
        <source>A choose-your-own adventure with branching paths.</source>
        <target state="translated">分岐していく“自分で選ぶ”タイプの冒険書式だ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="78">
      <segment>
        <source>We need you to traverse it.</source>
        <target state="translated">君にそこを踏破してきてほしい。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="79">
      <segment>
        <source>As you're the most familiar with [[[scp-2975|impermanent reality as a writing gimmick]]], you'll be leading the task force for this mission."</source>
        <target state="translated">[[[scp-2975|“移ろう現実”を執筆ギミックとして]]一番よく分かっているのは君だ。だからこの任務では隊を率いてくれ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="80">
      <segment>
        <source>
Sally glanced over to Gordon, picking his teeth in the corner. "</source>
        <target state="translated">
サリーは隅で楊枝を噛みながら歯をほじっているゴードンをちらりと見やった。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="81">
      <segment>
        <source>Surely Gordon's more qualified?</source>
        <target state="translated">ゴードンの方が適任じゃない？」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="82">
      <segment>
        <source>Some of his fans have //got// to have experimented with Twine or some shit back in the day."</source>
        <target state="translated">昔、Twine とかその手のので遊んでたファン、//絶対//いるでしょうし。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="83">
      <segment>
        <source>
"They did, yes.</source>
        <target state="translated">
「確かにやっていた。ああ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="84">
      <segment>
        <source>It was a rather popular trend for a few weeks.</source>
        <target state="translated">数週間ほどは結構な人気だった。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="85">
      <segment>
        <source>But he tended to... bulldoze his way through them, as he is wont to with most things.</source>
        <target state="translated">だが彼は…いつものことだが、ゴリ押しをする癖があるんだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="86">
      <segment>
        <source>No branching paths, no reader choice.</source>
        <target state="translated">だから分岐も、読者の選択も発生しなくなる。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="87">
      <segment>
        <source>Hardly stories at all, really.</source>
        <target state="translated">もはや物語と呼べた代物じゃない。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="88">
      <segment>
        <source>That was after the time loop trend, though, so he was... rather unhinged at the time."</source>
        <target state="translated">タイムループ流行の直後だったから、あの時期の彼は……かなり迷走していた。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="89">
      <segment>
        <source>There was a rare look of pity on the director's face, and for the first time Sally considered the full implications of having to remember your past iterations.</source>
        <target state="translated">部門長の顔に珍しく同情の色が浮かび、サリーは初めて「過去の繰り返しを記憶しなければならない」ということの重さを正面から思い描いた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="90">
      <segment>
        <source>
It was hard to feel bad for the asshole kicking Reggie in the shins, though.</source>
        <target state="translated">
……もっとも、レジーのすねを蹴っているそのクソ野郎に憐れみを抱くのはやっぱり難しかったが。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="91">
      <segment>
        <source>
"I guess that's that, then.</source>
        <target state="translated">
「じゃ、決まりでいいか。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="92">
      <segment>
        <source>Adventure, here we

-----

**Draft 3:**

Gordon raised his head, alarmed.</source>
        <target state="translated">冒険の幕開け――さあ――

-----

**ドラフト3:**

ゴードンがはっとして顔を上げた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="93">
      <segment>
        <source>
"We're in a masturbatory draft loop!"</source>
        <target state="translated">
「自己満足なドラフトループに落ちてるぞ！」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="94">
      <segment>
        <source>he barked. "</source>
        <target state="translated">と彼は吠え、「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="95">
      <segment>
        <source>Someone say something interesting, grab the readers' attentions."</source>
        <target state="translated">誰か何か面白いこと言って読者の注意引け！」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="96">
      <segment>
        <source>
[[collapsible show="Behind Gordon hung a large gun safety poster."</source>
        <target state="translated">
[[collapsible show="ゴードンの背後には大きな銃器安全ポスターが掛かっていた。"</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="97">
      <segment>
        <source>hide="It wasn't a very well-made poster, but the author is only learning GIMP, so cut them some slack."]] </source>
        <target state="translated">hide="出来は大して良くないが、作者はまだ GIMP を勉強中なので大目に見てほしい。"]]</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="98">
      <segment>
        <source>
[[image gun_safety.png size="medium"]]
[[/collapsible]]

"Look, this

-----

**Draft 4:**

isn't working."</source>
        <target state="translated">
[[image gun_safety.png size="medium"]]
[[/collapsible]]

「ほら、これは――

-----

**ドラフト4:**

うまく行っていない。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="99">
      <segment>
        <source>
Sandra[[footnote]] If you haven't caught on yet, any time there's a new lady's name here it's Barker, from earlier.</source>
        <target state="translated">サンドラ[[footnote]] まだ分かってない読者向け：ここで新しい女性名が出るたび、それはさっきのバーカーだ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="100">
      <segment>
        <source>She's doing her narrative shapeshifting thing.</source>
        <target state="translated">彼女は物語的シェイプシフトをしている。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="101">
      <segment>
        <source>That's her gimmick.- Opulent Overvoid[[/footnote]] scratched her nose, curious. "</source>
        <target state="translated">それが彼女のギミックなのだ。- Opulent Overvoid[[/footnote]] サンドラは鼻をかきながら首をかしげた。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="102">
      <segment>
        <source>What isn't?"</source>
        <target state="translated">何が“うまく行っていない”の？」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="103">
      <segment>
        <source>
"This drafty thing he's trying.</source>
        <target state="translated">
「彼がやってるこのドラフトごっこだよ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="104">
      <segment>
        <source>He's being too clever and meta, not paying enough attention to the story.</source>
        <target state="translated">賢ぶってメタに偏りすぎ。肝心の物語を見てない。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="105">
      <segment>
        <source>In a couple hundred words

-----

**Draft 5:**

we haven't done anything remotely fucking interesting."</source>
        <target state="translated">この数百単語で――

-----

**ドラフト5:**

ろくに面白いこと一つ出来てない。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="106">
      <segment>
        <source>
"Come on, that's bullshit, we've-"

At the head of the table, Penelope coughed, and all heads turned.</source>
        <target state="translated">
「おい、それは言い過ぎだ、俺たちは――」

卓の端でペネロペが咳払いし、全員の視線が向いた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="107">
      <segment>
        <source>It was a rather commanding cough.</source>
        <target state="translated">それはかなり指揮権を帯びた咳だった。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="108">
      <segment>
        <source>
"Gordon is absolutely right.</source>
        <target state="translated">
「ゴードンの言うとおりだ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="109">
      <segment>
        <source>We've already lost..." She looked down at her phone, tapping the screen a couple times. "...</source>
        <target state="translated">もう既に失っている…」彼女は端末を見下ろし画面を数度タップした。「…</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="110">
      <segment>
        <source>two readers, if our metrics are correct.</source>
        <target state="translated">読者二人をな。指標が正しければ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="111">
      <segment>
        <source>We'll earn a downvote for heavyhanded exposition with this very conversational track, but I believe it will be worth it.</source>
        <target state="translated">この過度に会話ベースの露骨な説明でダウンボートを受けるだろうが、価値はあると信じている。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="112">
      <segment>
        <source>I have a plan."</source>
        <target state="translated">策はある。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="113">
      <segment>
        <source>

Gordon shrugged, his enormous jacket audibly shifting.</source>
        <target state="translated">

ゴードンは肩をすくめ、巨大なジャケットがごそりと音を立てた。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="114">
      <segment>
        <source>
"Downvotes don't mean fuckall."</source>
        <target state="translated">
「ダウンボートなんてクソほど意味ねぇ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="115">
      <segment>
        <source>I've done the Reddit thing.</source>
        <target state="translated">Redditは散々経験してる。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="116">
      <segment>
        <source>They only delete if the author puts some horrible shit in."</source>
        <target state="translated">削除されるのは作者が胸糞ぶち込んだ時だけだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="117">
      <segment>
        <source>He scowled. "</source>
        <target state="translated">彼は顔をしかめた。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="118">
      <segment>
        <source>I still remember that shit, though.</source>
        <target state="translated">でもあのクソは全部覚えてる。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="119">
      <segment>
        <source>It fucks you up.</source>
        <target state="translated">頭の中ぐちゃぐちゃになるんだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="120">
      <segment>
        <source>The kind of shit the author isn't even comfortable having me //mention// right now."</source>
        <target state="translated">作者が今ここで俺に//言及//させるのさえ嫌がる類いのやつだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121">
      <segment>
        <source>
"This isn't Reddit, we don't think."</source>
        <target state="translated">
「ここはRedditじゃない――はずだ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="122">
      <segment>
        <source>We don't even know whether upper truth //has// a Reddit.</source>
        <target state="translated">上位真実にRedditが//存在するか//さえ分かっていない。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="123">
      <segment>
        <source>Our research shows that when data points drop below a certain merit threshold, they disappear entirely, from all planes.</source>
        <target state="translated">一定の評価閾値を下回ったデータポイントは全平面から完全に消失する――研究結果はそう示している。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124">
      <segment>
        <source>Penelope's assistant,[[footnote]] The fuck was her name, again?</source>
        <target state="translated">ペネロペの助手が、[[footnote]] えっと名前なんだった？</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="125">
      <segment>
        <source>She's not at all relevant to the story, really, except to prompt Penelope to acknowledge the beliefs of coldposters and such.</source>
        <target state="translated">物語的には全然重要じゃない。ペネロペにコールドポスターの信念とかを拾わせるためだけの役だ。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="126">
      <segment>
        <source>Oh, it doesn't matter.</source>
        <target state="translated">まあどうでもいい。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127">
      <segment>
        <source>We'll call her Mary. -</source>
        <target state="translated">メアリーってことにしよう。 -</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="128">
      <segment>
        <source>Over-This Overvoid[[/footnote]] Mary, piped up from behind her. "</source>
        <target state="translated">Over-This Overvoid[[/footnote]] メアリーが後ろから口を挟んだ。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="129">
      <segment>
        <source>Not //all//, Dr. Panagiotopolous."</source>
        <target state="translated">全部ではありません、パナギオトポウロス博士。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="130">
      <segment>
        <source>
"Right, of course."</source>
        <target state="translated">
「そうだな。当然だ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="131">
      <segment>
        <source>Penelope rubbed her cheekbone, prominent under her thin skin. "</source>
        <target state="translated">ペネロペは薄い皮膚の下で浮き上がる頬骨を指でこすった。「</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="132">
      <segment>
        <source>There are occasional instances where they remain on just a single plane, utterly fruitless.</source>
        <target state="translated">例外的に単一平面だけに残存して実を結ばないケースはある。</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
    <unit id="133">
      <segment>
        <source>That plane is always the original budding plane, the one belonging to their writer entity."</source>
        <target state="translated">そういう場合、その平面は常に芽吹きの起点となった原初平面――その作家実体に属する面――だ。」</target>
      </segment>
    </unit>
  </file>
</xliff>
